Guide to the Left Wing Political Activities Printed Material, 1966-2007
Left Wing Political Activities Printed Material, 1966-2007
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Left wing political activities printed material, 1966-2007
3650
2.6 cubic ft.
Newspapers, broadsides, brochures, clippings, newsletters, pamphlets, notes, and correspondence.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Consists primarily of printed items, newspapers, broadsides, brochures, clippings, newsletters, and pamphlets, mostly relating to Cornell University and its student organizations. Also includes notes and correspondence.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Consists primarily of printed items, newspapers, broadsides, brochures, clippings, newsletters, and pamphlets, relating to Cornell University and its student organizations and other organizations. Includes notes and correspondence. Topics documented include the Black Panther Party; Bobby Seale; Collegetown disturbance, Ithaca, New York, May 13, 1972; Cornell Aeronautical Laboratory (CAL); Giap-Cabral Community; Ithaca Labor Committee; May Day 1971; New American Movement; New Haven 9; the occupation of Carpenter Hall, Cornell University; Students for a Democratic Society; TIOHERO, leaflets gathered in San Francisco, 2007-2008. A number of circa 1972 materials, some published by Glad Day Press, from Ithaca Anti-War Coalition, Peoples Coalition for Peace and Justice, Ithaca United Action Against Imperialism, Peoples Anti-Fascist Resistance League, Southern African Liberation Committee, Ad hoc Committee to Combat Cornell Complicity, and the Committee of Concerned Asian Scholars at Cornell. Poster for The Red Detachment of Women event sponsored by the New China Study Group, China Program Students.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Seale, Bobby, 1936-; Black Panther Party.; Cornell Aeronautical Laboratory.; Ithaca Labor Committee.; New American Movement (Organization).; New Haven Nine.; Students for a Democratic Society.; Cornell University--Students.
Subjects:
Tiohero.; May Day.; Political clubs.; Radicalism.; College students--Political activity.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Revolutionary People's Constitutional Convention, September 4-7, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Revolutionary People's Constitutional Convention, November 1970 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Fall 1970, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Spring 1971, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- May Day and Spring 1971 (Part 1) (Box 1, Folder 5)
- May Day 1971 (Part 2) (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Growing Police State, 1968-1971 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Cornell, 1968-1971 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Information on Ithaca, 1968-1971 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- SDS Stuff, 1970-1971, 1968-1971 (Box 1, Folder 10-11)
- SDS Housing Program, 1968-1969, 1968-1971 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- SDS: Student Power, ROTC, Open Admissions, Anti-Recruiting, Other Rallies, Internal Education, Etc., 1968-1969, 1966-1971 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- The Left, 1969-1970, 1968-1970 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Washington, D.C., November 1969, 1969-1970 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Syracuse, March 19, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- New Haven, May 1970, 1969-1970 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Movement, June-July 1970, 1968-1970 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Ithaca, June-July 1970 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- West Coast, August 1970 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Spring, 1972, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Giap-Cabral; Ithaca United Action Against Imperialism; C-Town Riot(s); Winter-Spring, 1972, 1967, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Giap-Cabral, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Harrisburg, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Fall, 1971, 1970-1971 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Cambodia, May Strike, 1970; Washington, May 8-9, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- New American Movement, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Miscellaneous, 1968-1971 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Pamphlets: Liberation News Service; "What is Guerilla Theatre, Anyway?"; "The Destruction of Vancouver," Roy Stone; "Anarchist Peril," August Hamon; "No Treason: The Constitution of No Authority," Lysander Spooner; "Behind the Corporate Image ..."; "El Machete," Vol. 1, num 4; "Solidaire," no. 4, 1965-1973 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Publications: "Struggle!," vol. 1, no. 3; "How Many Vietnams..."; New Age"; "The Daily Californian," vol. 210, no. 30; "Augur," vol. II, no. 13; "The Rag," vol. 5, no. 19; "Berkeley Tribe," v. 5, no. 14, issue #94, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Photographs, 1968-1970 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Radical and SDS flyers, 1969-1972 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- TIOHERO/Glad Day Press: Publications Received, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- TIOHERO/Glad Day Press: Publications Received, 1971-1972 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- TIOHERO, Correspondence, 1970-1971 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- TIOHERO, Miscellaneous, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- TIOHERO, 1970-1971 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Volunteers, 1969-1970 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Various materials collected by Jean Dickson '72, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  Includes Glad Press items, material relating to Giap-Cabral Community and the Carpenter Hall takeover, Vietnam, Sharpeville Week, Apartheid in South Africa, America's War in Indo-China: The Last Phase by Committee of Concerned Asian Scholars at Cornell, Cornell, Corporations and War by the Ad hoc Committee to Combat Cornell Complicity, Cornell Aeronautical Lab, Ithaca Anti-War Coalition, Peoples Coalition for Peace and Justice, Ithaca United Action Against Imperialism, Peoples Anti-Fascist Resistance League, Southern African Liberation Committee. Poster for The Red Detachment of Women event sponsored by the New China Study Group, China Program Students. Daily Sun articles about Carpenter Hall takeover.
- Miscellaneous, 1968-1972 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Alternative Papers, 1970-1972 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Ithaca Labor Committee, 1968-1971 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Spring '72, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- N.A.M. Spring 1972, 1971-1972 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Davenport N.A.M. Conference, 1971-1972 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- N.A.M. Conference, Davenport, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Pamphlet: Labor Library, June, 1894 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Pamphlet: What Is a Pacifist?, 1916 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Pamphlet: Reasons Why You Should Vote Communist, 1934 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Pamphlet: A Labor Party for the United States, 1936 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Pamphlet: Terror Against the People, 194? (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Pamphlet: Your Dollar under Roosevelt, 194? (Box 4, Folder 8)